# Julián M. Del Fiore

Computer Networks Ph.D. Student

C229 - ICube Laboratory 300 Bd Sébastien Brant 67400, Illkirch-Graffenstaden Bas-Rhin, France ୬ +33 (0) 7 68 70 05 46 ⊠ delfiore@unistra.fr Argentinian/Italian Born December 20, 1990



# At a glance

Currently, as part of my Ph.D. "Verifiable Data Plane", I have performed large-scale active-measurement campaigns in order to evaluate the discrepancies between the control and the data plane on the Internet from multiple vantage points, over time. I have developed a modular framework that enables several combinations of conservative heuristics whose aim is to filter noise generated by, for example, incomplete traces, sibling ASs, IXPs or third-party addresses. Concerning my previous work, before starting my Ph.D. I worked on Industrial Wireless Networks and participated in the implementation of a cross-layer protocol that improves on the performance of the currently used in 6TiSCH networks (RPL+TSCH) for the Industry 4.0. The work was done in ContikiOS and the simulations run in COOJA.

I am an enthusiastic hard-worker Engineer that is interested in learning and constantly improving his knowledge. I am always looking forward to new challenges in my career: I started with Electronics, moved to Industrial Wireless Networks, and now I am getting involved with Cored Networks. I love learning new languages and exploring other cultures, reasons why I have moved to France. I like discussing and sharing knowledge, either by teaching or by collaborating with new people in any research project.

## Professional experience

2018 - Now **Assistant Teacher**, Télécom Physique Strasbourg - University of Strasbourg, France, Courses: TCP/IP, Algorithms and Programming in C.

2017 - Now Researcher, ICube Laboratory, Strasbourg, France,

Subject: "Verifiable Data Plane" Supervisors: Cristel Pelsser.

2017 Research Intern, IMT Atlantique, Rennes, France,

Subject: "Toward Reliable and Deterministic Networks in Industrial-IoT applications"

Supervisors: Dr. Georgios Z. Papadopoulos and Prof. Nicolas Montavont.

#### Education

2017 - Now  $\,$  **Ph.D. Student**, University of Strasbourg, France.

2010 - 2017 **Electronic Engineer**, University of Buenos Aires, Argentina,

Diploma of Honor – Final Average: 8.69/10.

2004 - 2009 English Bilingual Electronic and Electromechanical Technician, Escuela Philips, Argentina, Final Average: 8.87/10.

#### List of Publications

- 2019 "Filtering the Noise to Reveal Inter-Domain Lies", Julián M. Del Fiore, P. Merindol, V. Persico, C. Pelsser, A. Pescape. Under submission In TMA 2019.
- 2018 "From Best-Effort to Deterministic Packet Delivery for Wireless Industrial IoT Networks", R. A. Koutsiamanis, G. Z. Papadopoulos, X. Fafoutis, <u>Julián M. Del Fiore</u>, P. Thubert, N. Montavont. In IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics 2018. Impact Factor: 6.764
- 2017 "Towards Deterministic Industrial Networks", M. Kersalé, G. Z. Papadopoulos, Julián M. Del Fiore, P. Thubert, N. Montavont. In AlgoTel-CoRes 2017 (French speaking conference).

# Scholarships

- 2017 Now Initiative D'Excellence (IdEX), Ph.D. funding provided by French National Research Agency as part of the "Investments for the future" program.
- 2016 2018 YPF Foundation, granted to only 200 students across all Argentina, due to academic excellence.

## Complementary Education

- 2018 TMA Ph.D. School 'Hands on Big Data for TMA', presented poster at Network Traffic Measurement and Analysis Conference (TMA) Ph.D. School
- 2018 **Machine Learning**, completed Andrew Ng Coursera's course: introduction to machine learning, datamining, and statistical pattern recognition.

#### Awards

- 2008 Argentinian Chemistry Olympiad Level 1/3, 1st prize.
- 2007 Argentinian Chemistry Olympiad Level 1/3, 3rd prize.
- 2007 Argentinian Physics Olympiad 3rd prize.

## Organized Events

2018 **Cryptocurrency: Blockchain Technology** - Seminar introducing to Bitcoin Blockchain technology and other Blockchain applications.

#### References

Cristel **Professor**, ICube Laboratory, University of Strasbourg, France.

 ${
m Pelsser}$   ${
m pelsser@unistra.fr}$  -  ${\it Ph.D.\ Supervisor}$ 

Pascal Associate Professor, ICube Laboratory, University of Strasbourg, France.

Merindol merindol@unistra.fr - Ph.D. Co-Advisor

Georgios Associate Profesor, IMT-Atlantique, Rennes, France.

Papadopoulos georgios.papadopoulos@imt-atlantique.fr - Internship Supervisor

## Languages

Spanish - Mother Tongue , English - Advanced, French - Intermediate

#### Interests & hobbies

Guitar, Photography, Traveling